We created a form which we simply set up in javascript then which we then handled dynamically with our own
Sadece kendi girdi bileenimizle dinamik olarak ilediimiz javascript'te kurduumuz bir forum oluturduk ve
input component and our inputChangedHandler where we immutably update any effect that form elements,
girdi deiti ileyici biz yabanc unsurlarn herhangi bir etkisini deimez bir ekilde gncelledi.
now let's make sure we can also submit this form.
imdi bu formu da gnderebileceimizden emin olalm.
For that, we have the button with the clicked handler
Bunun iin tklanan ileyici ile dmeye sahibiz.
and I don't want to use to clicked handler,
Ve ileci toplamak iin kullanmak istemiyorum.
there actually is an
Gerekten var.
onSubmit event handler we can use on the form itself. And there, I want to now execute the method we
Olay ileyicisi gnderirken formun kendisinde de kullanabiliriz ve u anda gnderimde
used for that, the orderHandler onSubmit.
sipari ileyicisi iin kullandmz yntemi yrtmek istiyoruz.
Now in the orderHandler, I now of course still want to prevent the default,
imdi sipari ileyicisinde elbette varsaylan nlemek istiyoruz.
we still get an event object here automatically passed by react.
Hl tepki gstererek otomatik olarak getiiniz bir olay nesnesi alyoruz.
Now I want to prevent the default because I don't want to send the request automatically that would
imdi varsaylan nlemek istiyorum, nk isteimi otomatik olarak gndermek
reload my page, instead
istemiyorum, bunun yerine sayfam yeniden ykleyeceim.
I now need to extract the data
imdi verileri karmam lazm.
I want to submit and the cool thing is all the data is already managed in this state, in our form object
Gndermek istiyorum ve serin bir ey, bu verilerin zaten bu durumda ynetildii ve Form nesnemiz
here, which is updated all the time with two way binding, the value is updated at least and the value is certainly
burada her zaman iki balama ile gncelleniyor ve bu deer en az gncelleniyor ve deer kesinlikle
what I'm interested in.
de ilgilendiim ey.
I can create a new constant,
Yeni bir sabit yaratabilirim.
let's maybe name it formData and there, I want to get the data from my state and I want to basically
Belki veri formunu adlandralm ve oradaki verileri almak istiyorum ve element trn ve e atmasn
get my order form object here, though I don't care about the element type and the element config,
umursamam olsam da temel olarak sipari form nesnemi almam istiyorum.
I just want to get the name and then the value directly mapped to each other.
Sadece ismi almak istiyorum ve sonra dorudan birbirine elenen deer.
So I will transform it a little bit, for this formData can be an empty object initially and then I'll
Bu yzden, bu form iin veri dnm biraz deitireceim, balangta bo bir nesne olabilir ve sonra
loop through my form
formumun tamam dngye dnebilir.
So there I'll have my form element identifier in this.state.orderForm,
Dolaysyla hepsi de bu durum sipari formunda form esi tanmlaycm var.
so this very long form element identifier is simply email, country and so on.
Yani bu ok uzun form unsuru ve yangn sadece e-posta lke ve benzeri.
And then, I want to set formData for a given form element identifier equal to this.state.orderForm
Ve sonra form esi tanmlaycs ve exista deeri iin bu durum sipari formuna eit belirli bir
for the form element identifier and there access the value.
form esi tanmlaycs iin form verisi ayarlamak istiyorum.
So I simply create key value pairs where I have, where I add a new property to form data,
Dolaysyla, yalnzca yabanc veriler iin yeni bir mlk eklemek zorunda olduum anahtar deer iftleri olutururum.
a property like country, like email and so on
E-posta gibi lke gibi bir mlk vb.
and I set the value of that property not equal to an object but simply to the value the user entered.
Ve ben bu mlkn deerini bir nesneye eit deil, yalnzca kullancnn girdii deere ayarladm.
And now with this, I have that simple mapping,
Ve imdi bu basit haritalamam var.
I can now use that to submit it
imdi bunu sunmak iin kullanabilirim.
So here my formData, this is in the end what I want to pass
Yani burada form verilerim sonunda gemek istediim eyi yapyor.
so there I'll add an order data property to my order object and set this equal to formData.
Bylece sipari nesnem iin mlkiyet sipari tarihi ekleyeceim ve yabanc verilere eit olarak ayarlayacam.
And now let's see if this works in the way I want it to work,
imdi de ie yarayp yaramayacan grmek istiyorum.
let's also go to firebase for that.
Bunun iin de ate alanna gidelim.
So I'm in firebase, here are my orders,
Buras gvenlik merkezimde emirlerim.
let's now add a new order and see if that works. For that, I'll go through the full process,
imdi yeni bir sipari ekleyelim ve ie yarayp yaramayacana bakalm, tam ilemden geeceim.
I'll create a burger, click order now,
Tm tccar burgeri imdi tklayn.
continue, continue here and then set up some data
Buraya devam etmeye devam edin ve sonra baz veriler oluturun.
here, street, zipcode, some random code, United States maybe test@test.com
Sokak posta kodunuz baz rasgele kod Birleik Devletler belki de test com adresinde test edin.
Let's pick cheapest here and click order,
Burada en ucuzu seip tkla.
we are redirected, let's now have a look at firebase, a new order was added
Yeniden ynlendirildiimizde, yeni bir emir eklendiinde gvenlik merkezine bakmayalm.
and then, we have ordered data where we indeed have all these mappings where we have the data the user
Ve daha sonra, kullanclarn girdii verilere sahip olduumuz tm elemelere sahip olduumuz
entered. So submitting the form works just fine and in a very dynamic way,
verileri sipari ettik, bylece form gnderilmesi ok iyi ve ok dinamik bir ekilde iliyor.
look how easy it is to add a new input.
Yeni bir girdi eklemek ne kadar kolay grnyorsun.
You simply add a new property to your order form in the state, set up the element type, configure it
Eyalette, sipari formunuza yeni bir mlk eklemeniz yeterliyse, buradaki eyi yaplandrn ve bir deer
here and assign a value and you quickly added a new input.
atayn yazn hzl bir ekilde yeni bir girdi ekleyin.
And of course since this is in the state, you can even manipulate this order form immutably at runtime,
bylece dinamik olarak yeni zellikler ekleyebilir, yeni girdiler gelitirebilir veya deitirebilir veya yaplandrmay deitirebilirsiniz.
so you can dynamically add new properties, enhance new inputs or remove them or change the configuration.
Ve elbette bu durumdadr nk bu sipari formunu alma zamannda deimez ekilde de deitirebilirsiniz;
That is why such a dynamic way of creating a form is so awesome.
Bu yzden byle bir dinamik forum oluturma forumu harika.